Over there, huh...
（パックン）あそこか
Any closer and I'll be noticed...
（パックン）
これ以上 近づくと気づかれるか
Big Sister...
（エビゾウ）姉ちゃん
Are you taking those
with you?
そいつを持っていくのか？
Fate must have meant
for this to happen...
（チヨ）これも何かの縁じゃ
あやつと やり合うのに
これ以上のものはないからな
Nothing will serve me better
than these
if I'm gonna fight against him...
I've lived too long a life...
わしも長生きしすぎた
♪～
～♪
The Retired Granny's Determination
（はたけカカシ）なるほど
So...that's where his hideout is.
ここに ヤツらのアジトが
Most likely.
おそらくな
我愛羅のにおいも
同じ場所からしとった
Gaara's scent was also coming
from that same place.
I see.
（カカシ）なるほど
I have one more favor to ask you.
もう１つ 頼みがあるんだけど
（パックン）ん？
Huh?
（ナルト）う～ん
おっ うくっ…
いっ たたた…
Hey, are you awake, Naruto?
（パックン）
おう 起きたか ナルト
Huh? Pakkun...
（ナルト）あれ パックン
Okay, Pakkun, I'm counting on you.
（カカシ）
じゃあ パックン よろしく
See you around then, Naruto!
じゃあ またな ナルト
（ナルト）あっ
Kakashi Sensei!
カカシ先生
ひょっとして
暁あかつきのアジトが分かったのか？
Could it be that you've found
the Akatsuki's hideout?
Yeah... We're heading out immediately.
（カカシ）ああ すぐに出発するぞ
うん
What, Gaara's whereabouts
have been--?!
（テマリ）
何？ 我愛羅の居場所が？
（砂すなの里さとの忍）
はい 先ほど判明したそうです
Yes ma'am! His whereabouts
have just been located.
木こノ葉はの方々は
すぐに出発するとのことです
The Leaf are preparing
to depart immediately!
Understood! Gather
our skilled men immediately!
（テマリ）分かった
こちらも すぐに手練てだれを用意しろ
I will be heading out as well!
（テマリ）私も出る
（砂の里の忍）はっ
Yes, ma'am!
Temari...
（カンクロウ）テマリ
（カンクロウ）うっ…
Kankuro, don't be so reckless!
カンクロウ ムチャだ
You need to stay in bed
and take it easy!
お前は おとなしく寝てろ
I will get Gaara back,
no matter what!
我愛羅は 必ずこの手で取り戻す
All right, as soon
as the Sand is ready,
（カカシ）
では 砂の用意ができしだい
we'll join them for Gaara's rescue.
彼らと共に
我愛羅君を救出に向かう
Got it?
いいな
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
（テマリ）待たせたな
（春野はるのサクラ）あっ テマリさん
Temari!
Everyone's here...
（カカシ）そろったな
All right! Then let's head out!
よーし
じゃあ 出発だってばよ
Wait!
（バキ）待て
（ナルト）あ？
Temari... You and the others stay here
in the village and patrol the border.
テマリ お前たちは
里に残って国境警備に当たれ
どういうことだ それは
What do you mean by that?!
That's an order from...above.
（バキ）上からの命令だ
Huh...?
あ…
風影かぜかげ様の不在が公になれば
Their reasoning is...
if it becomes widely known that
the Kazekage is absent,
いつ よその里が攻めてきても
おかしくないという理由でな
there's no telling when other villages
will attack our village...
（砂の里の忍）そんな…
I can't believe this...
That's all the more reason that
だからこそ 一刻も早く
我愛羅を取り戻すべきではないのか
we have to get Gaara back
as soon as possible!
These Leaf people came
all this way
ここにいる木ノ葉の者たちも
わざわざ 我愛羅を助けるために
来てくれているのだぞ
for the very purpose of
going to Gaara's aid!
Gaara is our  Kazekage, right?!
我愛羅は我々の風影ではないか
砂の人間が行かなくて
一体 どうする！
What's the point if we,
the Sand people, don't go to save him!
But...
（バキ）しかし…
I'm going.
（チヨ）わしが行く
（チヨ）砂の忍は
わし１人で十分じゃ
The only Sand Shinobi
you need is me!
チヨバア様
Granny Chiyo!
But that's...
あ… しかし それは…
もともと 隠居の身
I am already retired, you know...
I can do whatever I like.
どう行動しようと わしの勝手じゃ
そんな… 無理をなさらないほうが
You really shouldn't overdo it...!
Don't you dare treat me
like an old woman!
（チヨ）
わしを年寄り扱いするでないわい
たあっ！
あっ 飛んだ
She jumped!
（ナルト･サクラ）わっ！
Wha--?!
かわいい孫を 久しぶりに
かわいがってやりたいんでの
I haven't doted on my dear grandchild
for a while, after all...
All right, we'll head out.
（カカシ）
じゃあ 我々は出かけます
Sorry... I will try to convince
the higher-ups...
すまん
これから なんとか
上役たちを説得してみる
We'll follow behind later,
no matter what!
必ずあとから行くからな
（サクラ）うん
（ナルト）はっ そのころには
Gaara will be long rescued
by that time!
とっくに 我愛羅を
助け出してるってばよ
See you later!
（サクラ）いってきます
（カンクロウ）うっ
う… くっ
クソっ
Damn! If only I were
physically fit.
この体さえしっかりしてりゃ
There'd be no stopping me
from going...!
絶対に俺が行くってのに
（テンテン）
ちょっと飛ばしすぎだって
Hey, we're going a little too fast!
We haven't stopped running
since we left!
（テンテン）
もう ずっと走りっぱなしじゃない
少しは休憩しようよ
Let's take a little break!
Tenten, you need more training!
（ロック･リー）テンテン
修行が足りませんね
Lee! In front of you!
（日向ひゅうがネジ）リー 前だ
（リー）あっ
（マイト･ガイ）ああっ
（テンテン）あっ
Wait, Guy!
待て ガイ
（ガイ）んっ！ パックン
Pakkun!
Naruto!
ナルト
１つ 聞いてもいい？
Can I ask you something?
いつから暁に狙われてたの？
Since when have you been
targeted by the Akatsuki?
うっ
I don't know...
分かんねえ
There was that one time when
two people from the Akatsuki
（カカシ）１度 暁の中の２人が
ナルトに接触しに
木ノ葉まで来たことがあった
came to the Leaf Village in order to
make contact with Naruto.
あれから３年
But that was three years ago...
and they've just started
making a move now.
今になって動き始めた
I don't know why.
理由は分からないがな
Why did they wait three years?
どうして３年も待ったんだろ？
It could be that it's not because
they didn't want to,
（カカシ）
手を出さなかったんじゃなくて
出せなかったのかもしれないな
but because they couldn't.
Because Lord Jiraiya was always
hanging close to Naruto...
ナルトには 常に
自来也じらいや様がついていたからな
No...
（チヨ）いや
Based on information I acquired,
there apparently is another reason.
わしの得た情報では
もっと別の理由があると聞いた
Another...reason?
（ナルト）別の理由？
There's quite a bit of
preparation involved
人に封じられている
尾獣びじゅうを引き剥がすには
if one's gonna draw out the Tailed Beast
that's sealed within people.
それ相応の準備がいるからのう
それに手間取ったのじゃ
They encountered difficulties
with that.
What's this "Tailed Beast"
that you were talking about?
今の話… 尾獣って？
なんじゃ 綱手つなでの弟子のくせして
What?!
You're Tsunade's disciple
and you don't even know that?!
そんなことも知らんのかい
The Leaf Village had
a Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit...
木ノ葉には 九尾きゅうびがおったろうが
（ナルト）あっ
（サクラ）あっ
The Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit is
（カカシ）九尾のことは
木ノ葉では 完全に極秘扱いですので
treated as top secret
amongst the Leaf Village...
まあ それもそうかのう
Well, that's not surprising, I guess...
A Tailed Beast refers to
Beast Spirits with tails.
尾獣とは 尾を持つ魔獣のことじゃ
Long, long ago,
the Sand had a One-Tail.
砂は昔から一尾いちびを持っておる
それが我愛羅に封じられた
守鶴しゅかくのことじゃ
That's the Shukaku sealed
within Gaara.
One-Tail?
一尾
Do you mean that there are
other beasts
それじゃあ 九尾以外にも
そんな魔獣が？
besides the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit?
（チヨ）そうじゃ
That's right...
There are a total of nine
tailed beasts in this world...
この世に 尾獣は全部で９体おる
Tailed beasts have
special characteristics.
尾獣には特徴があってな
Each of them have
a different number of tails.
それぞれ尾の数が違う
The One-Tailed has one tail.
The Two-Tailed has two.
一尾には尾が１本
二尾にびには２本
And up to the Nine-Tailed
as the name suggests,
それらが 九尾までその名のとおり
each name represents
the number of tails the beast has.
名が尾の数を表すのじゃ
The Tailed beasts have
immense Chakra
尾獣は バク大なチャクラの塊で
and in the world of Ninja,
忍界にんかい大戦期には 各国
隠れ里が軍事利用しようと
they were used for military purposes
by Hidden Villages around the world.
競って
手に入れようとしたものじゃ
They competed to get
their hands on them.
But no one was able
to control that power
しかし 人知を超えたその力を
制御することなど
which surpassed human intelligence.
誰にもできなんだ
I don't know why
the Akatsuki is after it,
暁がなんのために
それを欲しとるのか 分からんが
but that power is too dangerous...
危険すぎる力じゃ
But in this new peaceful age,
the Tailed beasts apparently...
まあ 平穏な情勢の中
時代も移ろい
今や尾獣は
still exist, having scattered
all around the world...
世界各地に ちりぢりに
存在しておるらしいがの
（パックン）
カカシに言われ わしら八忍犬はちにんけんは
Kakashi directed us,
the Eight Ninja Hounds,
バラバラに八方に散り
to fan out in every direction
暁の連中のにおいを追った
to follow the Akatsuki
Organization's scent.
そうしたところ…
While we were doing that,
we realized that
ヤツらは 木ノ葉と砂の間にある
川の国へと向かった
those guys were headed towards
the Land of Rivers
which is situated between
the Leaf and Sand.
川の国？
The Land of Rivers...?
そうじゃ
That's right.
つまり 今現在
暁の最も近くにいるのは
In other words,
you guys are closest to the Akatsuki
at this point in time.
木ノ葉から
砂へ向かってきていた...
You, who were heading from
the Leaf to the Sand Village.
お前らだ
（テンテン）あっ
なるほど
I see...
Follow me...
I'll explain the details as we run.
（パックン）わしについてこい
詳しいことは 走りながら説明する
（ガイ）よし みんな 行くぞ
All right! Let's go, everybody!
（テンテン）え～ もう？
Huh? Already?
An enemy is nearing
this hideout.
（ゼツ）このアジトの近くに
敵が近づいているぞ
An enemy, you said?
（デイダラ）敵だと？
And a highly skilled one at that.
（ゼツ）それも相当の手練れだ
His name is...Might Guy.
これは 名はマイト･ガイ
（暁リーダー）誰だ？ そいつは
Who's that?
（うちはイタチ）木ノ葉の上忍じょうにんで
体術を使う かなりのやり手だ
A Leaf Jonin Ninja who
uses Taijutsu.
He's one clever operator.
Don't underestimate him.
甘く見ないほうがいい
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）ああ～
Ah...that freak beast, huh...
あの珍獣ですか
We will use that Jutsu...
（暁リーダー）あの術をやる
（飛段ひだん）それなら俺が行く
In that case, I'll go...
I was getting irritated for not
having any luck finding a Jinchuriki.
人柱力じんちゅうりきが
なかなか見つからなくてな
イライラしてたところだ
No, I'll go...
（鬼鮫）いいや 私が行きましょう
その人には個人的に
ちょっと因縁がありましてね
I have something of a personal quarrel
with him, you see...
（暁リーダー）そうだな
You're right. That Jutsu is more suited
to someone like you.
あの術は 暁の中でも
チャクラ量の多いお前向きだからな
Among the Akatsuki,
you are more heavily loaded
with Chakra, Kisame.
鬼鮫
（鬼鮫）ハハッ はい
Yes...
（暁リーダー）それでも
チャクラの30パーセントはもらうぞ
Even so, I'll take 30%
of your Chakra.
（鬼鮫）ったく
やれやれ やっと…
Well, well, well...
It looks like I'll finally be
able to get pay back
あのときの蹴りの借りが
返せそうですね
for that kick he gave me...
（ガイ）木ノ葉剛力旋風このはごうりきせんぷう
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
（鬼鮫）うわあ！
（ガイ）ふっ
Who the heck is he?
何者です？
（ガイ）木ノ葉の気高き碧あおい猛獣
The Noble Blue Beast of
the Leaf Village... Mighty Guy.
マイト･ガイ
（ガイ）どうした？
What's up?!
（パックン）誰か来る
Someone's coming!
（テンテン）うっ
白眼びゃくがん
Byakugan!
後ろだ！
Behind us!
（テンテン）んっ
（リー）ハア
（ガイ）んっ
あっ
You...
お前は…
Do you know him, Guy Sensei?!
知ってるんですか？ ガイ先生
Who are you?
（ガイ）誰だ？
（テンテン）ああ…
（ゼツ）また来たぞ
Another guest...
（暁リーダー）今回は
やけに騒がしいな デイダラ
It's a little noisy this time,
isn't it, Deidara!
あ… いや
Well, the Jinchuriki was
stronger than the other two...
今回の人柱力は
ほかの２人より強かったんだよ うん
（サソリ）
だから 俺が最初に言ったろうが
I told you at the start, didn't I?
Your Jutsu wasn't suited
for covert operations.
お前の術は 隠密行動には
向いてねえってな
（デイダラ）はっ
そういう旦那のトラップも
I'd say your traps were
pretty loud too, weren't they?
結構 派手だったんじゃねえのか
うん
What!
（サソリ）なにを！
（暁リーダー）仲間割れはよせ
Stop fighting amongst yourselves!
今は術に集中しろ
Concentrate on the Jutsu!
さて 今度は誰が行く
Now then...
who should I send this time...
（飛段）今度こそ俺の番だな
This time it's my turn,
without any doubt.
（ゼツ）今度も木ノ葉の忍だ
Another Leaf Shinobi...
（飛段）チッ
Damn!
In that case, it's decided...
（暁リーダー）じゃあ 決まりだ
（カカシ）みんな止まれ！
Everybody, halt!
（ナルト）うっ
誰？
Who is that?
（カカシ）いきなりですか
Out of the blue, huh...
（チヨ）こヤツ あの目…
That guy...those eyes...
お前は…
You're...
This guy...has a ridiculous amount
of Chakra.
こいつ とんでもないチャクラ量だ
これほどのチャクラ量を
持ってるヤツを見たのは
ナルト以来だ
（リー）そんなに？
本当に覚えてないと？
あっ お前 まさか…
思い出したようですね
俺と会ったことがあるのか？
珍獣は 頭のほうも
獣レベルのようですね
まあ すぐに思い出させて
差し上げますがね
うちはイタチ
あっ
こ… この人が？
この人が… うちはイタチ
♪～
～♪
あれは なんですか？ ガイ先生
リーよ あれこそが 我々の
待ち焦がれていたものだ
では あれが
サーファーたちの憧れの的
数年に１度やってくるという
伝説の大波
ビッグサーズデイ！
行け リーよ
今こそ あの荒れ狂う大波を制し
男になるチャンスだ
押忍！ 見ていてください
ガイ先生
僕のファイティングスピリットを
証明してみせます
そのノリ やめなさい
次回「因縁
あいまみえる」
（リー）今回は
木ノ葉に刻まれた 青春の思い出
秘蔵写真の数々を
僕が紹介していきますよ
まずは 生まれたばかりのナルト君
ナルト君にも
こんな時代があったんですね
なっ これは
３代目と伝説の３人です
ポニーテールの綱手様
とてもイケてます
こちらは
４代目とカカシさんたちです
６歳で中忍ちゅうにんになったそうですよ
さすが ガイ先生の永遠のライバル
この写真は 今でも枕元に
大切に飾られているそうです
では おなじみの方たちを
一気にご紹介です
これは アカデミー生のころですね
うわ～ 懐かしいです
そして これがサクラさん
のおお～！
ビュ… ビューティフルすぎです
笑顔がまぶしすぎて
まっすぐ見られません
最後は りりしい眉に
ぱっちり おめめの美少
そう 木ノ葉の美しき碧き野獣こと
この僕です
決まった